Guide to the James R. Dumpson Papers circa 1922-2015 MS 3078
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Fordham University, 1965-1996; 1 Linear Feet
  - Fordham University. Social Work Accreditation Site Visitor, circa 1991-1992 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fordham University [binder] (2 folders), 1992-2008 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Fordham University. Career highlights and Guide to the James R. Dumpson Papers [at Fordham], circa 1994 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 14)
  - Odyssey Forum [Fordham?] (2 folders), 1996 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 15-16)
- Series VI. International Social Welfare, 1952-2001; 5 Linear Feet
  Series VI brings together material documenting James R. Dumpson's social welfare work in the international sphere, notably from his time in the 1950s as United Nations Advisor and Chief of Training in Social Welfare to the Government of Pakistan, and from his work in South Vietnam during the 1960s and 1970s for the Unitarian Universalist Service Committee and the U.S. Senate Sub-Committee on Refugees and Escapees.
  Series V is sorted first alphabetically, by the name of the country or city of interest, and then chronologically under that place.
  - Geneva. Conference on Employment Problems, 1964 July 20-24 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ghana, 1984 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ghana (4 folders), 1999-2001 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3-6)
    In 2000 James R. Dumpson was installed as Nana Bonsu Abadio by the Minister of Culture Nana Akuoko Sarapong of the Republic of Ghana.
  - Hong Kong. Reading/Reference materials, International Social Welfare (2 folders), circa 1969-1978 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Hong Kong. Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group of the Asia Society (SEADAG) (2 folders), 1971-1975 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9-10)
  - Hong Kong. 20th International Conference on Social Welfare, 1980 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
  - Japan. Great Cities Study, 1976 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
  - Japan. 23rd International Conference on Social Welfare (4 folders), 1986 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13-16)
  - Kenya, 1974 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kenya, 1982 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kenya, 1984 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
  - Kenya & Ethiopia, 1984 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pakistan. Papers, memos, reports, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pakistan. Personal letters, 1953 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
    Includes poetry composed by Dumpson in the 1930s.
  - Pakistan. Reports to Eleanor Hinder UN-TIA (2 folders), 1953 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Pakistan. U.N. Reports (3 folders), 1952-1954 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Pakistan. U.N. Technical Assistance Administration Pakistan Social Welfare Project, 1953 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 12)
  - Pakistan. Published reports, 1954-1956 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 13)
  - Pakistan. Training for Social Work in Pakistan, 1955 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 14)
  - Pakistan. Fordham University Institute of Mission Studies, 1957 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 15)
  - Pakistan. Asia Foundation, 1961-1963, 1977 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pakistan. 18th International Conference on Social Welfare, 1976 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
  - Pakistan, 1977 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
  - Pakistan & Vietnam reports & miscellaneous, 1970s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
  - Thailand. ECAFE Seminar, vol. 1, 1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
  - Thailand. ECAFE Seminar, vol. 2, 1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
  - Thailand. Training for Family and Child Welfare, 1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Thailand. Thailand project [+ misc.], 1980s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Thailand. Field Instruction Project, 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - U.S.S.R. Leadership Conference, 1991 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ukraine trip, 1992-1993 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 11)
  - Vietnam. Social Welfare Background Material, 1962-1967 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 12)
  - Vietnam. James R. Dumpson in Saigon and Japan, 1967 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
  - Vietnam. Unitarian Universalist Service Committee (5 folders), circa 1969-1972 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14-18)
  - Vietnam. Interagency Vietnam Adoption Committee (IVAC) Materials, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam. Conference on Placement and Adoption of Vietnamese Children, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam. A.I.D. Meeting on Child Welfare in Vietnam, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam. Official memoranda, cables, etc., 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam. Senate Judiciary Subcommittee on Refugees, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam. Senator Kennedy's releases and others, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
  - Vietnam. Statistics, 1973 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
  - Vietnam. Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group of the Asia Society (SEADAG) (2 folders), 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Vietnam. General (1-7 of 9 folders), circa 1965-1974 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10-16)
  - Vietnam. General (8-9 of 9 folders), circa 1965-1974 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - International Social Development teaching materials (2 folders), 1986 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - International Social Welfare. U.N. Conference, 1968 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
  - International Social Welfare. General (7 folders), 1960s-1990s (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6-12)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous files, binders, and loose material, circa 1930-2015; 5 Linear Feet
  Series VII gathers a mix of single-topic files revolving around the perennial issue of social welfare that do not fold neatly into the preceding five series. Of particular interest are the folders covering Dumpson's time as administrator of the New York City Human Resources Administration (box 12, folders 14–15, and box 13, folder 1), and board chairman of the Health and Hospitals Corporation (box 12, folders 10–13). Series VII also includes a significant amount of loose material, and miscellaneous items that came to the New-York Historical Society in unlabeled binders.
  The files of Series VII are sorted alphabetically by their titles supplied by James R. Dumpson. The remaining folders of loose material and items from unlabeled binders are grouped in rough chronological order.
  - Baltimore NAACP Fiasco, 1962 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
  - Commissioner of Welfare reports, etc., 1957-1965 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
  - Council on Social Work Education, circa 1967-1974 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
  - Decentralizing Social Services in New York City, 1975 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
  - Dorsey, Norbert M., "Pierre Toussaint of New York", 1966 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Effects of Social Intervention, Book 1 [book draft], 1971 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
  - The Effects of Social Intervention, Book 2 [book draft] (2 folders), 1971 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - HARYOU-ACT Evaluation [Harlem Youth Opportunities Unlimited-Associated Community Teams], 1965 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
  - HHC Clippings (2 folders), 1962-2005 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - HHC [New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation] Memos, 1990-1993 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
  - HHC / Dinkins Administration, 1991-1993 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
  - [HRA Budget Crisis] (2 folders), 1965-2002 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14-15)
  - HRA and the Dumpson Administration, 1965-1977 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Interviews, circa 1988-1994 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Many Faces of Aging: Challenges for the Future, 1995 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Black Leadership Commission on AIDS [binder], 1995-1998 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
  - National Conference on Social Welfare. Dumpson's presidency (2 folders), 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5-6)
    See box 22, volume 10 for The Social Welfare Forum, 1972. Official Proceedings, 99th Annual Forum, National Conference on Social Welfare, Chicago, Illinois. The conference was originally planned for Anaheim, California, but switched to Chicago when area activists pointed out the tone-deafness of the NCSW in funneling revenue into a city that ignored the plight of its disadvantaged ethnic minorities.
  - Newburgh, N.Y. welfare problems, 1961 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 7)
  - New York Community Trust Retirement, 1981 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 8)
  - News clippings, program announcements, and clippings re: JRD, circa 1937-1988 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 9)
  - Non-Profit Decline & Dissolution Project Report, circa 1967-1978 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 10)
  - Northside Center for Child Development. Board Meeting, 2009 October 1 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 11)
  - Northside Center for Child Development. Board Meeting, 2009 December 3 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 12)
  - Proposal abstract, circa 1977-2007 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 13)
  - Publicity & Publications, 2003 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
  - Removing Risks from Children [book draft] (3 folders), circa 1997 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1-3)
  - Status of Black New York Report [Professor Alma Carten's reserve readings, New York University], 1984 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
  - Task Force on Social Services report (draft), 1966 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Task Force on "Welfare Reform." Book 1 (2 folders), 1938-2010 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6-7)
  - Task Force on "Welfare Reform." Book 2 (2 folders), 1938-2010 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 8-9)
  - Task Force on "Welfare Reform." Book 3 (2 folders), 1938-2010 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 10-11)
  - Tropnas, Joan. "Factors Associated with Social Support on African American Women With AIDS in their Parenting Role" [Fordham University Ph.D. dissertation], 1999 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 12)
  - Wilder litigation (3 folders), 1984, 1993 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1-3)
  - Loose material, 1930-1955 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Loose material, 1960-1966 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
  - Loose material, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
  - Loose material, 1970-1975 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
  - Loose material, 1976-1979 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
  - Loose material, 1980-1989 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Loose material, 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
  - Loose material, 1993-1999 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 11)
  - Loose material, 2000-2015 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 12)
  - Loose material, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous binder (2 folders), circa 1961-2009 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous binder (2 folders), circa 1967-1999 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Miscellaneous binder (3 folders), circa 1968-2002 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 5-7)
  - Miscellaneous binder, circa 1977-1993 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous binder (2 folders), circa 1981-2003 (Offsite-box 16, Folder 9-10)
- Series VIII. Print matter, 1922-2009; 6 Linear Feet
  Books, pamphlets, and periodicals assembled by James R. Dumpson over the course of his long life. Many bear his initials or signature inside the front cover or on the flyleaf. While most publications concern social welfare broadly, some focus on particular issues, such as aging, or black children in foster care. Some items—like a 1922 monograph on Renaissance art and poetry (box 20, volume 10)—appear to date from Dumpson's school years. Publications including chapters or contributions by Dumpson have been noted when obvious.
  Series VIII is organized in five sub-series:
  Sub-series VIII.A. Pamphlets and softbound publications, 1931-2005
  Sub-series VIII.B. Periodicals, 1955-2009
  Sub-series VIII.C. Government documents, 1951-1973
  Sub-series VIII.D. Hardbound publications, 1922-1992
  Sub-series VIII.E. Proceedings of the National Conference of Social Work, 1939-1981
  Except for Sub-series VIII.E, which is sorted chronologically, all publications are grouped alphabetically by title.
  - Sub-series VIII.A. Pamphlets and softbound publications, 1931-2005; 1.75 Linear Feet
    - Adolescents at Risk: Medical and Social Perspectives. Cornell University Medical College Seventh Conference on Health Policy | David E. Rogers and Eli Ginzberg, eds., 1992 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1)
    - Aging: An International Perspective. Proceedings of a Conference. Brookdale Institute on Aging and Adult Human Development, 1982 March 11 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 2)
    - AIDS: An Expanding Tragedy. The Final Report of the National Commission on AIDS, 1993 June (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
    - AIDS is Your Business: A Guide to Corporate HIV/AIDS Grantmaking, undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
    - American Public Welfare Association. Selected Biennial Round Table Conference Papers, 1963 December 4–7 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
      Includes James R. Dumpson, "The Human Side of Automation."
    - Beyond Civil Rights: The Right to Economic Security | James R. Dumpson, et. al, 1976 November (Offsite-box 17, Folder 6)
    - Beyond Tradition: New Models of Community-Based Family Services, 1994 May (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7)
    - The Case Against Urban Desegregation | Frances Fox Piven and Richard A. Cloward, 1967 January (Offsite-box 17, Folder 8)
    - Celebrating Social Work: Faces and Voices of the Formative Years | Elizabeth Wichers DuMez, ed, 2003 (Offsite-box 23, Folder 8)
    - Child Welfare League of America, Inc. Implementing Adoption Assistance & Child Welfare Act of 1980 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 9)
    - Child Welfare Revisited: An Africentric Perspective | Joyce E. Everett, ed, 2004 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 10)
      Includes Alma J. Carten and James R. Dumpson, "Family Preservation and Neighborhood-Based Services: An Africentric Perspective."
    - Children Need Families: A Second Look at Delinquency Prevention, 1955 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 11)
    - Colored Orphan Asylum (2 pamphlets), undated (Offsite-box 17, Folder 12)
      Contains:
      Colored Orphan Asylum: A Short Account of its History, Work and Present Needs (undated).
      The Story of Riverdale Children's Association, Founded in 1836 as the Colored Orphan Asylum (undated).
    - Commission on Accreditation, Roster of Certified Site Visitors, Council on Social Work Education, 1990-1992 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 13)
    - Community Values and Conflict, 1967: A Conference Report (Offsite-box 17, Folder 14)
    - A Comparison of Diagnostic and Functional Casework Concepts. Report of the Family Service Association of America Committee to Study Basic Concepts in Casework Practice | Cora Kasius, ed, 1950 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 15)
    - Conserving New York State's Most Important Resource, 1975 April (Offsite-box 17, Folder 16)
    - Dedication of the Black Press Archives and Gallery of Distinguished Newspaper Publishers on the Occasion of the Sesquicentenary of the Founding of the Black Press in the United States. Morrland-Spingarn Research Center, Howard University, 1977 March 18 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 17)
    - A Death in the Family: Orphans of the HIV Epidemic | Carol Levine, ed, 1993 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 18)
    - Economically Productive Aging in New York City: Employment Opportunities and Constraints, 2005 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 19)
    - Essentials of Social Work Programs in Hospitals (Chicago: American Hospital Association), 1971 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 20)
    - Ethnic Minorities in Social Work Education | Carl Scott, ed, 1970 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 21)
    - Evaluating Student Learning: Baccalaureate Programs and the Community College Transfer Student | Edward J. Mullen, 1976 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 22)
    - Facing the Challenge. Plenary Session Papers from the 19th Annual Program Meeting. Council on Social Work Education, 1973 February (Offsite-box 17, Folder 23)
    - Foster Care 1984: A Report on the Implementation of the Recommendations of the Mayor's Task Force on Foster Care (Offsite-box 17, Folder 24)
    - Maestri del Colore: Giotto in Assisi (Bergamo: Istituto Italiano d'Arti Grafiche), 1957 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 25)
    - Growing Older in New York City in the 1990s: A Study of Changing Lifestyles, Quality of Life, and Quality of Care, volumes 3-5, 1993 September (Offsite-box 17, Folder 26)
      Volume 3 | The Impact of Health Problems on the Quality of Life of Older New Yorkers
      Volume 4 | New York City as a Place of Residence for Older People: Life Space, Environment, and Impact of Crime
      Volume 5 | Family and Community Support Systems of Older New Yorkers
    - Human Services for the Asian American Elderly in New York City, 1996 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 27)
    - The Impact of Welfare on Family Stability | Blanche Bernstein and William Meezan, 1975 June (Offsite-box 17, Folder 28)
    - International Council on Social Welfare. "The Relationship Between ICSW and Governmental Bodies: Reality and Expectations", 1982 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 29)
    - Interviews, Interviewers and Interviewing in Social Case Work. Articles Reprinted from "The Family" (New York: Family Welfare Association of America), 1931 (Offsite-box 17, Folder 30)
    - Leaving Foster Care: Black Children Returning to Home and Community, 2002 October (Offsite-box 17, Folder 31)
    - Living in Harlem: A Survey of Residents' Attitudes, 1973 November (Offsite-box 17, Folder 32)
    - The Metropolitan Life Survey of the American Teacher 1993. Violence in America's Public Schools (Offsite-box 17, Folder 33)
    - The Metropolitan Life Survey of the American Teacher 1994. Violence in America's Public Schools: The Family Perspective (Offsite-box 17, Folder 34)
    - Minority Elders: Longevity, Economics, and Health. Building a Public Policy Base, 1991 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 1)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, [1978] (Offsite-box 18, Folder 2)
    - The Nature of Process: Its Implications for Social Work | Saul Hofstein, 1964 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 3)
    - New York City Child Care Programs: Challenges Ahead, 1974 July (Offsite-box 18, Folder 4)
    - New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation's Response to Stanley H. Lowell's Report, Special Counsel to the Health and Hospitals Corporation of New York | James R. Dumpson, 1991 November 20 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 5)
    - North American Approaches to Meeting Human Needs: Some Issues and Challenges, 1981 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 6)
    - Northside Center for Child Development. Annual Report, 1980-1981 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 7)
    - Ohio's African-American Males: A Call to Action. Volume 2, Education, Health, Employment and Criminal Justice. (Columbus, Ohio: Ohio Office of Black Affairs), 1990 June (Offsite-box 18, Folder 8)
    - Personnel in Anti-Poverty Programs: Implications for Social Work Education, 1967 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 9)
    - Perspectives on Social Work Education in the 1970s: A Report of a Faculty Development Workshop. Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, 1971 September (Offsite-box 18, Folder 10)
    - Prescription for Longevity: Fads and Reality, 1997 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 11)
    - Proceedings of the Black Family Summit Convened by: The National Urban League, Inc. & The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1985 March (Offsite-box 18, Folder 12)
    - Proceedings of the New York State Conference on Children's Rights. New York State Senate Sub-Committee on Children's Rights of the Judiciary Committee, New York State Assembly Committee on the Judiciary, 1974 April 3–4 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 13)
    - Professional Social Worker in Public Social Welfare | Lawrence Podell, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 14)
      Introduction by James R. Dumpson.
    - Proposals Concerning Professional Qualifications and Education for Professional Social Welfare Workers (Working Party on Social Welfare Education), 1986 August 1 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 15)
    - Redirecting Foster Care: A Report to the Mayor of the City of New York (3 copies), 1980 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 16)
    - Report of Ad Hoc Committee on Public Welfare to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1961 September (Offsite-box 18, Folder 17)
    - Social Work With Older People: Understanding Diversity (undated) (Offsite-box 18, Folder 18)
    - Ruth Williams Memorial Lectures | Margaret Hickey, ed, undated (Offsite-box 18, Folder 19)
    - Services for People: Report of the Task Force on Organization of Social Services, U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1968 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 20)
    - Seventh NASW [National Association of Social Workers] Professional Symposium: "Social Work Practice in a Turbulent World", 1981 November 18-21 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 21)
    - Some Economic Effects of Discrimination in Employment, 1967 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 22)
    - The State of Black America 1987 (National Urban League, Inc.), 1987 January (Offsite-box 18, Folder 23)
    - A Survey of Leadership Attitudes Toward the Quality of Life in Harlem, 1973 November (Offsite-box 18, Folder 24)
    - The Tarrytown Conference: The Shaping of Social Welfare Policy, 1983 November 13–15 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 25)
      Preface by Dumpson.
    - Three Public Policy Issues in Perspective (2 copies), 1990 January (Offsite-box 18, Folder 26)
    - Title XX Senior Services: The First Year, 1976 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 27)
    - Toward a More Humane Society. Graduate School of Social Service, 2000 Dean's Report. Fordham University. (5 copies) (Offsite-box 18, Folder 28)
    - Toward Education for Effective Social Welfare Administrative Practice | James R. Dumpson et. al, 1978 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 29)
    - Training for Social Services in Public Welfare Agencies and the Role of Institutions of Higher Learning, 1976 September (Offsite-box 18, Folder 30)
    - Unplanned Parenthood: Grandparents Raising Grandchildren, 1995 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 31)
    - Urban Development in the United States: Implications for Social Welfare | Lawrence K. Northwood, 1966 September (Offsite-box 18, Folder 32)
    - U.S. Immigration Policy and Global Interdependence, 1982 June (Offsite-box 18, Folder 33)
    - Why the Ghetto Must Go | Sterling Tucker, 1968 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 34)
    - Workshop on Street Children, 1999 November 23-24 (Offsite-box 18, Folder 35)
  - Sub-series VIII.B. Periodicals, 1955-2009; 0.75 Linear Feet
    - Administrative Science Quarterly, vol. 23, 1978 September (Offsite-box 18, Folder 36)
    - Child Welfare Watch, vol. 17, 2009 Winter (Offsite-box 18, Folder 37)
    - Dædalus: Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, vol. 103, no. 2, "Slavery, Colonialism, and Racism.", 1974 Spring (Offsite-box 18, Folder 38)
    - Foundation News: The Journal of Philanthropy, vol. 15, no 4, 1974 July/August (Offsite-box 18, Folder 39)
      Photo of Dumpson p. 5.
    - Health & Social Work: A Journal of the National Association of Social Workers, vol. 1, no. 1, 1976 February (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1)
    - International Social Work, vol. 31, no. 3, 1988 July (Offsite-box 19, Folder 2)
    - Journal of Current Social Work Thought, vol. 2, no. 1, 1969 June (Offsite-box 19, Folder 3)
    - Public Welfare: The Journal of the American Public Welfare Association, vol. 19, no. 4 (2 copies), 1961 October (Offsite-box 19, Folder 4)
      Includes James R. Dumpson, "Public Welfare and the Newcomer in the Community"
    - Public Welfare: The Journal of the American Public Welfare Association, vol. 20, no. 3, 1962 July (Offsite-box 19, Folder 5)
    - Public Welfare: Journal of the American Public Welfare Association, vol. 51, no. 1, 1993 Winter (Offsite-box 19, Folder 6)
    - SCAA Viewpoint: An Occasional Publication Concerning Public Health and Social Welfare, no. 15, 1968 Winter (Offsite-box 19, Folder 7)
      Includes James R. Dumpson, "Breaking the Barriers to Self-Esteem for Millions of Americans"
    - Social Work Education Reporter (scattered issues), 1969–1972 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 8)
    - Social Work Education Reporter (scattered issues), 1973-1976 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 9)
    - The Welfarer [published by the New York City Department of Welfare], vol. VII, 1955 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 10)
    - The Welfarer [published by the New York City Department of Welfare], vol. VIII, 1956 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 11)
    - The Welfarer [published by the New York City Department of Welfare], vol. IX, 1957 (Offsite-box 19, Folder 12)